JAY DIRAN SWEET

jaydiran@gmail.com 206.949.4886 Kirkland WA

Github: Jay-TechSalon LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/jdiransweet

Profile

I am a developer who strives to create relevant experiences, focusing on design environments where both the end-user and my client will benefit. My background centers around my passion for knowledge, an infinity to constantly see the world as micro interactions, and a desire on crafting strategies based on these observations.

Skills

Technical Skills Practical Skills HTML5 JavaScript User Workflows Responsive Design CSS3/Sass Design Strategy Wire Framing **SMACSS** Information Hierarchy Agile Workflow Git/Terminal Visual Design Angular Js **jQuery Project Leadership** Photoshop Team Building Jade

Projects

Tutorius - Angular App

-4 day team project providing an MVP based on an educational component. This Angular app provides instruction & interaction to help understand binary trees. -HTML5, CSS3, Angular, JavaScript, Git, Kanban, Personas, Wireframes, User Workflows *Highlights*: project leadership & team building with 3 JS Devs & 2 UX Devs. Front end to backend integration with Angular, complete Git workflow, MVP/5days/67hours

Quick*Note - Web App

-A place to take notes, on and off-line, regardless of the device or locally installed system fonts. Takes advantage of HTML5's ability to store content locally on device. -HTML5, CSS, Local Storage, AppCache, Git, JavaScript, jQuery *Highlights*: small team, Git workflow, GitHub management, deploying online

Background Image Clip - File API

-Uploader that clips the image into the hidden text, creating a graphic design poster like effect that can be replaced again and again with each new upload.
-HTML5, CSS3, Local Storage, AppCache, Git, JavaScript, DOM manipulation *Highlights*: working with an API and understanding key value pairs, using Git

Experience

Creative, Apple Inc Bellevue, Wa 2011-2014

Teacher for Apple Retail, trainer of Apple technology with our One to One members. *Highlights*: intensive training at Apple, Cupertino 2012. Effective strategies to present complex ideas to both large groups and individuals in a atmosphere of learning.

Full Time Student, LWIT Kirkland, Wa 2009-2013

- -Multi Media Design Program, focusing on Video and Web Production
- -Bachelors of Technology in Applied Design

Highlights: becoming and avid learner, focusing in media production, web technologies, design thinking, design strategy, and project presentation ε leadership.

Education

Code Fellows 2014

Certificate, Front End UX Design & Development

Lake Washington Institute of Technology 2011-2014

B.A., Applied Design - Honors

Lake Washington Technical College 2009-2011

A.A., Multimedia Design -Honors